No man can walk out of his own story.
Rango is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Gore Verbinski.
When Rango, a lost family pet, accidentally winds up in the gritty, gun-slinging town
of Dirt, the less-than-courageous lizard suddenly finds he stands out.
Welcomed as the last hope the town has been waiting for, new Sheriff
Rango is forced to play his new role to the hilt.
Rango / Lars (voice), played by Johnny Depp.
Beans (voice), played by Isla Fisher.
Mayor (voice), played by Ned Beatty.
Rattlesnake Jake (voice), played by Bill Nighy.
Priscilla (voice), played by Abigail Breslin.
Roadkill (voice), played by Alfred Molina.
Rango is a 2011 American animated Western comedy film directed
by Gore Verbinski and written by John Logan.
The film stars Johnny Depp as Rango, with Isla Fisher, Abigail Breslin, Alfred Molina, Bill
Nighy, Harry Dean Stanton, Ray Winstone and Timothy Olyphant in supporting roles.
In the film, an anthropomorphic pet chameleon ends up in the town of
Dirt, an outpost that is in desperate need of a new sheriff.
The film contains a number of references to various other films, including The Shakiest Gun in the West, A Fistful of Dollars, Chinatown,
The Good, the Bad and the Ugly, Once Upon a Time in the West, Cat Ballou, Raising Arizona and Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas.
Verbinski has also cited El Topo as an influence on the film.
Visual effects and animation for the film were
outsourced to Industrial Light & Magic.
Rango premiered on February 14, 2011, at Westwood, Los Angeles, and was
released in the United States on March 4, by Paramount Pictures.
The film received acclaim from critics and grossed $246
million worldwide against a $135 million budget.
At the 84th Academy Awards, Rango won Best Animated Feature.
Following its critical and commercial success, Rango would
lead to the formation of Paramount Animation.
The film explores themes of hero, gunslinger, sheriff, nevada, mayor.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.